

HARDWARE ENGINEER . LOGIC AND EMBEDDE

23205 SE Black Nugget RD C8, Issaguah, WA 98029

Summary_

Recent M.Eng. graduate from Cornell University in Electrical and Computer Engineering. Interests span from creating and programming **Embedded Systems** to **Computer Architecture** and **ASIC design**. Experienced with both embedded Linux platforms such as the Raspberry Pi and DE1-SoC, and bare-metal platforms like the PIC32. Well-versed in **C**, **Python** and **Verilog**.

Education

Cornell University Ithaca, NY

M.Eng. in Electrical and Computer Engineering

Aug. 2016 - Aug. 2017

- GPA: 3.673
- Relevant Courses: Advanced Computer Architecture, Embedded Operating Systems, HL Digital Design Automation, Complex Digital ASIC Design, Advanced Microcontroller Design, Parallel Programming

Cornell University Ithaca, NY

B.S. IN ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

. Aug. 2012 - May 2016

- · Minor: Computer Science
- Dean's List: Spring 2014, Fall 2015, Spring 2016
- Relevant Courses: Computer Architecture, Designing with Microcontrollers, Digital VLSI Design, Telecommunications, Operating Systems, Embedded Systems

Work Experience_

Cornell College of Engineering

Ithaca, NY

GRADUATE TEACHING ASSISTANT FOR DIGITAL VLSI DESIGN

Jan. 2017 - May 2017

May 2013 - Dec. 2016

- Held weekly office hours to assist students with concepts and problem sets.
- Graded problem sets and exams. Graded live demos of lab assignments.
- Wrote problems for problem sets and exams. Test drove several labs to verify feasibility.

Cornell Information Technology

Ithaca, NY

COMPUTER LAB OPERATOR

- Supervised the use of various computer labs across campus.
- Provided technical support for lab patrons.
- Ensured that the printers were stocked and operational.
- Prepared specialty classrooms for Professors before classes.

Cornell Academic Technologies Center

Ithaca, NY

STUDENT TECHNOLOGY ASSISTANT

May 2013 - May 2016

- Provided technical support to professors for various pieces of software.
- Checked out devices such as cameras to professors.
- Performed media conversions (analog to digital) for professors.

Clad Network, Inc. (Start-up company)

Ithaca, NY

LEAD HARDWARE ENGINEER

Oct. 2014 - Sept. 2015

- Discussed business and technology strategy with the rest of the team.
- Implemented adaptive lighting system for our product on an Arduino microntroller.
- Created a networking solution for the onboard embedded Linux platform in our product.

Wallaby Yogurt Company

Napa County, CA

June 2014 - July 2014

Engineering and Maintenance Intern

- Maintained and updated an Access database used for parts inventory.
- Setup virtual environments for testing database software.
- Devised a mobile monitoring system for the plant.
- Performed maintenance on the video surveillance system and the wireless network.
- Assisted in the installation of automation hardware.

SEPTEMBER 1, 2017 WILLIAM ABAJIAN · RÉSUMÉ